<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Capital In, Capital Out]]></title>
  <link href="http://cappio.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cappio.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-12T15:12:30-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://cappio.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cappio]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Generation's Most Overlooked Skill: Investing]]></title>
    <link href="http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/02/12/our-generations-most-overlooked-skill/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-12T12:00:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/02/12/our-generations-most-overlooked-skill</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Want to be rich? Lucky for you, <a href="https://www.quora.com/How-should-a-22-year-old-invest-his-her-money/answer/Ching-Ho">Ching Ho on Quora</a> laid out a roadmap for us - “a boring yet tried-and-true investment method that will make you rich over time, richer than most rappers who&rsquo;ll blow their money on cocaine&hellip;”</p>

<h4>How to Make 10 Million Dollars:</h4>

<p><a href="https://www.quora.com/How-should-a-22-year-old-invest-his-her-money/answer/Ching-Ho"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/KcaqfZf.png" width="250"></a></p>

<p>Despite the fact that his plan is optimistic, you could very well go ahead and follow it. However, if you read his whole post carefully, it’s clear his takeaway is that individuals need to invest in themselves. To build this kind of wealth, he made two key assumptions: you must have skills to earn your own income and learn to take control of your own finances.</p>

<p>I want to build on Ching Ho’s philosophy and argue that regardless of whether you want $10 million or just want to retire comfortably, you will need to start gathering financial acumen now.  With interest rates nearing all time lows, all that money sitting in your savings account is not doing anything for your long term wealth.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> My generation especially - lovingly lumped together as “millennials” - can no longer afford not to. Together we must cultivate a generation of investors.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>How It Was</h3>

<p>For my parents, retirement planning was simple: work at one company for 30 years and retire on a pension and social security. They may have held some other small investments, but for most, holding down a steady job with a solid pension created a nice retirement lifestyle. But today, we won’t be fortunate enough to enjoy our parents’ ideas of retirement, and we’ll instead face greater financial uncertainty in our golden years.</p>

<h3>The Disappearing Pensions</h3>

<p>The era of the company pension has all but disappeared. Since 1998, the rate of Fortune 500 companies who offered pensions to new hires dropped from 60% to 24%. Now, only 7% of Fortune 500 employers offer new employees traditional pensions.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> These traditional pensions have static, defined payouts on retirement, based on the time and pay of the employee. To compensate, employers are moving towards 401(k) plans which is less risky for the company. This is because 401(k)s generally have variable returns based on employee investment choices. Regardless which retirement plan ends up better for employees, the trend is clear; individuals will now have to make thoughtful decisions on where their savings are placed.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/get-there/wp/2014/09/05/nearly-a-quarter-of-fortune-500-companies-still-offer-pensions-to-new-hires"><img src="http://note.io/16YSOM4" width="750"></a></p>

<p>Perhaps more importantly, even if pensions were still available, the average time a millennial stays at a job is 2-3 years: nowhere near enough to get a pension.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup> This trend does not seem to be slowing down as the stigma of short employment is disappearing. This is a strong indicator that individuals will have to take on managing investments themselves.</p>

<p>Read more about the <a href="http://www.fastcompany.com/1802731/four-year-career">4 year career here</a></p>

<h3>Live Long and Prosper?</h3>

<p>A simple factor that is commonly overlooked is that the average millennial is going to live longer than their parents. While this may be great news, it leaves our generation entering the workforce with two options: <strong>we either have to save more because our money will have to last longer, or we have to retire later.</strong></p>

<p>The problem is compounded with the crushing cost of education and healthcare. Even accounting for salary increases and inflation, these costs are continuing to rise at a frightening rate. Over the last 30 years, education costs have grown over 500% and health costs, nearly 300%.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> If you compare these numbers to the graph of inflation adjusted household income, it’s easy to see that this is a serious problem.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Household_income_in_the_United_States#mediaviewer/File:US_Real_Household_Median_Income_thru_2012.png"><img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/5c/US_Real_Household_Median_Income_thru_2012.png" width="750"></a></p>

<p>Don’t expect social security to bail anyone out either as it’s return is negligible for the middle class. It only pays out on average of $1,262/month, a rate which only rises ~10% (about $80 more per month) every year.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup></p>

<h3>What’s to Come</h3>

<p>To summarize, this generation is in a period with rising costs and stagnant incomes. Companies are reducing pensions in favor of employee-managed 401(k)s. These are just two factors that show why the burden of investment will continue to shift towards individuals rather than employers. So with the odds looking like they are all stacked against us, what are we millennials to do? While Ching Ho’s <em>How to Make 10 Million Dollar</em> plan may have seemed a little overkill in the beginning of this post, I hope you have seen how important it is for us to start learning how to financially plan for our future. For our next post, I’ll explore some investment philosophies and strategies that our new generation of investors are adopting. Hope you&rsquo;ll join us!</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://www.ritholtz.com/blog/2012/01/222-years-of-long-term-interest-rates">http://www.ritholtz.com/blog/2012/01/222-years-of-long-term-interest-rates</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/get-there/wp/2014/09/05/nearly-a-quarter-of-fortune-500-companies-still-offer-pensions-to-new-hires/">http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/get-there/wp/2014/09/05/nearly-a-quarter-of-fortune-500-companies-still-offer-pensions-to-new-hires/</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p><a href="http://www.bls.gov/news.release/tenure.t01.htm">http://www.bls.gov/news.release/tenure.t01.htm</a><a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-26/college-costs-surge-500-in-u-s-since-1985-chart-of-the-day.html">http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-26/college-costs-surge-500-in-u-s-since-1985-chart-of-the-day.html</a><a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p><a href="http://www.infoplease.com/ipa/A0780010.html">http://www.infoplease.com/ipa/A0780010.html</a><a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CappioNotes #2: PPC, LUV]]></title>
    <link href="http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/cappionotes-number-2-ppc/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-02T14:55:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/02/02/cappionotes-number-2-ppc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Quick Investment Ideas for Busy People</h2>

<p>Welcome back to the second edition of CappioNotes. Just like last time, we will give you some quick starting points for potential investments. This week we are covering:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="#ppc">Pilgrim&rsquo;s Pride</a></li>
<li><a href="#luv">Southwest Airlines</a></li>
</ul>


<h2><a name="ppc"></a>Pilgrim&rsquo;s Pride Corp (NASDAQ:PPC)</h2>

<ul>
<li>Great fundamentals with increasing cash flows and low debt.</li>
<li>Pilgrim’s Pride acquired Tyson Food‘s (TSN) Mexican poultry business for $400M. Expected to add $650M to annual revenues.</li>
<li>Paid a special cash dividend to shareholder of $5.77 a share. Shows confidence in future growth and shareholders.</li>
</ul>


<p>PPC isn’t typically regarded as the most exciting company to cover but their recent results say otherwise. Pilgrim’s pride is the second largest chicken producer in the world, having grown at an astronomical rate over the course of 2014. Their rock solid financials and continued efforts to grow make them a great investment for 2015.</p>

<h4>Rock solid fundamentals</h4>

<p>First and foremost, what makes PPC even worth considering is the financial stability it portrayed over the last year. Continually growing revenues, steady earnings growth, and excellent management of its debt levels helped the stock surge 131.08% over the past year. For the financially savvy out there, PPC’s debt-to-equity (a ratio of total liabilities to shareholder’s equity which indicates how to company is financing its assets) is very low at 0.25 and is currently below that of the industry average, implying that there has been very successful management of debt levels.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<!--more-->


<h4>Poised for Grow in 2015</h4>

<p>In efforts to keep up the substantial growth, PPC has acquired Tyson Foods, Inc.’s Mexican poultry business for $400 million dollars. The deal is expected to increase PPC’s revenues $650 million giving it a good boost on money coming in over the next year.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> The acquisition highlights PPC’s strategy to acquire vertically integrated companies to position itself in the industry for future growth. In addition, on January 28th, 2015, PPC paid out a special cash dividend of $5.77 a share to its shareholders as a testament to their financial discipline and confidence in the future.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>PPC’s positioning as a leader in the poultry production and distribution industry has given them a huge boost in 2014. With their continued efforts at aggressive expansion through acquisitions and dividend payouts, PPC is ready to keep rallying through 2015. And let’s be honest, who’s going to stop eating chicken anytime soon?</p>

<p>Check out their great fundamentals more in depth with our Cappio report:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=PPC"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/mpTyJza.png"></a></p>

<h2><a name="luv"></a>Southwest Airlines (NYSE:LUV)</h2>

<ul>
<li>Lower oil prices through 2015 will increase profitability for airline companies</li>
<li>Southwest is now flying to more destinations</li>
</ul>


<p>With oil prices on a monumental dive through 2014, multiple investment opportunities opened up for 2015. One of the bigger ones that every investor should be taking advantage of right now is the airline industry. It’s been a well known fact that the airline industry’s profit margins have been miniscule due to high oil prices. Now that the costs have been drastically decreased, there’s nothing standing in the way of Southwest Airlines from generating some serious money.</p>

<h4>Oil’s down, airlines are up</h4>

<p>The rationale for taking advantage of airlines right now is pretty straightforward. Oil has always been the majority of an airline’s costs and now that it’s floating around $40 a barrel, airlines are going to be netting a lot more money than they have in the past. As a quick example, Southwest Airlines expects its fuel bill for 2015 to be $1.7 billion lower than in 2014. If they don’t change a thing, they’ll be astronomically more profitable due to the lower oil prices alone.[^1] That kind of profitability will drive stock prices higher through earnings releases.</p>

<h4>Continuing the growth in 2015</h4>

<p>The reason Southwest Airlines is the airline of choice for 2015 is due to its solid growth over the course of 2014 and expansion plan in 2015. First off, Southwest Airlines was the top performer in the S&amp;P 500 in 2014 and that momentum isn’t going anywhere.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> Secondly, Southwest has started aggressively expanding its destination offerings by adding international and popular tourist destinations.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup> With the oil expense cut by more than half along with the fact that people are flying more than ever, the potential for Southwest to increase earnings is immense.</p>

<p>Southwest is a prime example of the type of the investments people should look into making in 2015 as low oil prices have opened the door to sizable returns. Check out some detials on Southwest’s performance here:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=LUV"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/WF3WmkF.png"></a></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s all for this week! Don&rsquo;t hesistate to comment or shoot us a note with questions at <a href="&#x6d;&#97;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#x68;&#x65;&#108;&#x6c;&#111;&#64;&#x63;&#97;&#112;&#112;&#x2e;&#x69;&#x6f;">&#104;&#x65;&#x6c;&#x6c;&#111;&#64;&#99;&#97;&#112;&#112;&#x2e;&#x69;&#111;</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://www.thestreet.com/story/13026139/1/pilgrims-pride-ppc-plummets-today-as-stock-begins-trading-ex-dividend.html">http://www.thestreet.com/story/13026139/1/pilgrims-pride-ppc-plummets-today-as-stock-begins-trading-ex-dividend.html</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="http://ir.pilgrims.com/releasedetail.cfm?ReleaseID=862275">http://ir.pilgrims.com/releasedetail.cfm?ReleaseID=862275</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p><a href="http://www.thestreet.com/story/13026139/1/pilgrims-pride-ppc-plummets-today-as-stock-begins-trading-ex-dividend.html">http://www.thestreet.com/story/13026139/1/pilgrims-pride-ppc-plummets-today-as-stock-begins-trading-ex-dividend.html</a><a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p><a href="http://money.cnn.com/2015/01/22/investing/southwest-airlines-earnings-fuel-savings">http://money.cnn.com/2015/01/22/investing/southwest-airlines-earnings-fuel-savings</a><a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p><a href="http://www.zacks.com/stock/news/160254/3-great-reasons-to-buy-southwest-airlines-luv-stock">http://www.zacks.com/stock/news/160254/3-great-reasons-to-buy-southwest-airlines-luv-stock</a><a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CappioNotes, First Edition (MSFT, GILD, DIS)]]></title>
    <link href="http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/01/21/cappio-quick-picks-first-edition/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-21T16:23:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/01/21/cappio-quick-picks-first-edition</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Quick Investment Ideas for Busy People</h2>

<p>We want to premiere the CappioNotes series as a way to jump start your own research by highlighting key insights we have gathered from reputable articles. Essentially, CappioNotes will be doing for qualitative analyst articles what our Cappio report does for quantitative financial data!</p>

<p>Today we are covering:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="#msft">Microsoft</a></li>
<li><a href="#gild">Gilead</a></li>
<li><a href="#dis">Disney</a></li>
</ul>


<h2><a name="msft"></a>Microsoft (NASDAQ:MSFT): Taking the Cloud</h2>

<p>After their Surface’s big flop in 2012, Microsoft has been under the radar the last couple of years, working hard to rebrand themselves. However, they&rsquo;ve come back into investor&rsquo;s sights with the recent appointment of their new CEO, Satya Nadella, in February of 2014. They&rsquo;ve also have made headlines in 2014 with their acquisitions of Mojang, most known for their game Minecraft, and Nokia. Among investors, they are also known for it’s huge dividend yield of 2.8%, one of the best payouts in technology sector. Over the last year the company’s stock grew nearly 30% &ndash; Here’s why we think you should a look at Microsoft this year before it start rallying again:</p>

<h4>Refocused efforts in cloud</h4>

<p>Microsoft has really turned their focus towards mobile and cloud technologies in the last years.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> They have already shown great growth in 2014 based on their cloud revenue numbers. Commercial cloud revenue has grown 128% in last quarter alone.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup> With Nadella leading the charge as a &ldquo;mobile first, cloud first&rdquo; company, there’s tremendous room for growth in 2015. This year, Microsoft is making a big push Microsoft’s mobile with lots of chat about what&rsquo;s to come of their Nokia aquisition.<sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<!--more-->


<h4>Cloud Computing industry as a whole is rapidly growing</h4>

<p>The cloud computing industry is growing like wildfire, with global spending reaching $150B in 2014.<sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup> There&rsquo;s no sign of that trend slowing down. An IHS report shows by 2017, enterprise spending on cloud computing will amount to a projected $235.1B.<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup> Microsoft has positioned itself to compete with Amazon and Google to dominate this market. Revenue’s have increased over the last year and Microsoft has managed to accumulate a good amount of cash to acquire key players in cloud and mobile to grow its own service offerings. This is obvious when you take a look  aquisition history that 8 of the last 10 were related to cloud or mobile technologies.<sup id="fnref:6"><a href="#fn:6" rel="footnote">6</a></sup></p>

<p>Overall, 2015 is looking really solid for Microsoft and there is a pretty high upside. Make sure to click the Cappio report below and check out a summary of Microsoft’s fundamentals:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=MSFT"><img src="http://note.io/1CTm40Y"></a></p>

<h2><a name="gild"></a>Gilead Sciences (NASDAQ:GILD): Steady.. for a Biotech</h2>

<p>Gilead Sciences is an American biopharmaceutical company with a focus on developing and commercializing therapeutics. For more background info check <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gilead_Sciences">the Gilead Wikipedia page</a>. GILD makes top shelf treatments like Harvoni, a hepatitis C drug with a very high cure rate. It boasts a functional cure rate of 99% in select patient types.<sup id="fnref:7"><a href="#fn:7" rel="footnote">7</a></sup> Harvoni has gotten lots of attention for both effectiveness and it’s price. Harvoni costs $1,125 a pill, or $94,500 for a 12-week course of treatment. It may seem outrageous but patients with hepatitis are still finding ways to pay for it.<sup id="fnref:8"><a href="#fn:8" rel="footnote">8</a></sup></p>

<p>Gilead has a long history of solid growth, but since it’s a biotech company, it’s stock price is pretty volatile. On an average day of holding GILD, you can expect to see price movement both upwards and downwards of 2-5%. However, they are a solid company and always dominate their industry in fundamentals. Here are some reasons why 2015 looks great for them:</p>

<h4>Solid Projections and High Growth Potential</h4>

<p>Gilead’s Q4 earnings will be out in the first week of February. We will see their hepatitis C drug, Harvoni, bring in solid sales and revenues. Analysts predict revenues of $6.75 billion overall and Earnings per Share of $2.28.<sup id="fnref:9"><a href="#fn:9" rel="footnote">9</a></sup> This should be a very reachable number for Gilead. Gilead did over $2 for all of 2013. They have also crossed over estimates  for most of 2014. Gilead has constantly beaten earnings, and there is a strong possibility they will beat them once again.<sup id="fnref:10"><a href="#fn:10" rel="footnote">10</a></sup> If they do, we expect a great jump in their stock price as other companies have had huge surges in recent months.</p>

<p>In December, Gilead also announced that it has entered into an agreement with Osaka, a Japan based Ono Pharmaceutical company. Together they are working to develop and commercialize ONO-4059 to treat B-Cell Malignancies. ONO will develop the drug and Gilead will pay for exclusive rights. Gilead will have exclusive rights to this drug almost everywhere except ASEAN countries, i.e. Japan, China, Taiwan, and South Korea.<sup id="fnref:11"><a href="#fn:11" rel="footnote">11</a></sup></p>

<h4>Booming pharmaceutical industry that doesn’t show signs of slowing</h4>

<p>The pharmaceutical industry was incredibly successful this past year, reaching over $1 trillion in spending . Annual spending is expected to grow 5-7%, which is the highest pace since 2009.<sup id="fnref:12"><a href="#fn:12" rel="footnote">12</a></sup> It is a high risk, high reward industry, due to a company’s success based on government regulation and FDA approval. The safest way to invest in this industry is to find companies that are extremely large, where one failed drug approval won’t cause the company to go bankrupt.</p>

<p>Gilead is a prime example of this philosophy as it is extremely large and has great fundamentals. Check out the Cappio report for a quick fundamental overview:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=GILD"><img src="http://note.io/1yJb9aY"></a></p>

<p>For additional reading on Gilead check out this article, <a href="http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2014/12/22/could-gilead-sciences-inc-be-a-top-stock-in-2015.aspx">Fool - Could Gilead be a Top Stock in 2015?</a></p>

<h2><a name="dis"></a>Disney (NYSE:DIS): Crowdpleaser, even for Investors</h2>

<p>If you’re looking for a blue chip stock with steady positive growth, Disney may fit your criteria. Their stock price is constantly breaking 52 week highs every quarter last year. This is because Disney has extremely <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mean_reversion_(finance)">low mean reversion</a> and high return on equity. This makes Disney a great mid-long term hold that won’t make you anxious. The best time to get it is in the present moment, because their stock price rarely looks back. Some reasons why Disney deserves some research are:</p>

<h4>Highly anticipated releases in 2015 to follow positive reception in 2014</h4>

<p>Their acquisition and growth of Marvel also shows how Disney capitalizes on opportunities. Big releases this year include a new Avengers movie, Ant-Man, and Star Wars. While it’s difficult to predict the performance in the box office, in 2014, Walt Disney Studios had 3 of the top 10 worldwide grossing movies.<sup id="fnref:13"><a href="#fn:13" rel="footnote">13</a></sup> It’s also worth noting that ESPN, a Disney subsidiary, never fails to top TV ratings.<sup id="fnref:14"><a href="#fn:14" rel="footnote">14</a></sup></p>

<h4>Investment in scientific research to keep spurring innovation and creativity</h4>

<p>Disney growth engine is sparked with creativity and imagination. Imagination creates the movies, which make millions of dollars in the box office. However Disney has also invested in developing a world class research team that works on all sorts of scientific experiments. This research helps Disney to enter a variety of consumer industries beyond films. They even make all their research publically available on their website. <a href="http://www.disneyresearch.com/projects/">See their latest research projects here.</a></p>

<p>Overall, Disney also has good fundamentals that can be taken a look at on our Cappio report:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=DIS"><img src="http://note.io/1yJdLpi"></a></p>

<p>For additional reading on Disney, check out this article, <a href="http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2014/12/09/3-reasons-walt-disney-co-stock-could-top-100-in-20.aspx">Fool - 3 Reasons Disney could top $100 in 2015</a></p>

<p>Well that concludes our first edition of CappioNotes. Look out for more to come and don&rsquo;t hesitate to ask us any questions on the comments below or shoot us a note at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#x3a;&#104;&#101;&#108;&#x6c;&#111;&#64;&#99;&#x61;&#112;&#112;&#46;&#105;&#x6f;">&#x68;&#x65;&#108;&#108;&#111;&#x40;&#x63;&#x61;&#112;&#x70;&#46;&#105;&#x6f;</a></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p><a href="http://www.zdnet.com/article/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-talks-mobile-first-cloud-first">http://www.zdnet.com/article/microsoft-ceo-satya-nadella-talks-mobile-first-cloud-first</a><a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p><a href="http://www.microsoft.com/investor/EarningsAndFinancials/Earnings/PressReleaseAndWebcast/FY15/Q1/default.aspx">http://www.microsoft.com/investor/EarningsAndFinancials/Earnings/PressReleaseAndWebcast/FY15/Q1/default.aspx</a><a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p><a href="http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2014/09/25/3-reasons-microsoft-stock-could-hit-60-by-2015.aspx">http://www.fool.com/investing/general/2014/09/25/3-reasons-microsoft-stock-could-hit-60-by-2015.aspx</a><a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2014/03/14/roundup-of-cloud-computing-forecasts-and-market-estimates-2014">http://www.forbes.com/sites/louiscolumbus/2014/03/14/roundup-of-cloud-computing-forecasts-and-market-estimates-2014</a><a href="#fnref:4" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p><a href="http://press.ihs.com/press-release/design-supply-chain/cloud-related-spending-businesses-triple-2011-2017">http://press.ihs.com/press-release/design-supply-chain/cloud-related-spending-businesses-triple-2011-2017</a><a href="#fnref:5" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:6">
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mergers_and_acquisitions_by_Microsoft">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mergers_and_acquisitions_by_Microsoft</a><a href="#fnref:6" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:7">
<p><a href="http://www.modernhealthcare.com/article/20141010/NEWS/310109947">http://www.modernhealthcare.com/article/20141010/NEWS/310109947</a><a href="#fnref:7" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:8">
<p><a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2014/12/19/this-drug-costs-1125-per-pill-and-is-about-to-shatter-sales-records">http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/wonkblog/wp/2014/12/19/this-drug-costs-1125-per-pill-and-is-about-to-shatter-sales-records</a><a href="#fnref:8" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:9">
<p><a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/2836226-50-percent-upside-for-gilead-in-2015">http://seekingalpha.com/article/2836226-50-percent-upside-for-gilead-in-2015</a><a href="#fnref:9" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:10">
<p><a href="http://www.estimize.com/gild">http://www.estimize.com/gild</a><a href="#fnref:10" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:11">
<p><a href="http://investors.gilead.com/phoenix.zhtml?c=69964&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=2000963">http://investors.gilead.com/phoenix.zhtml?c=69964&amp;p=irol-newsArticle&amp;ID=2000963</a> <a href="#fnref:11" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:12">
<p><a href="http://www.imshealth.com/portal/site/imshealth/menuitem.c76283e8bf81e98f53c753c71ad8c22a/?vgnextoid=96bdd595ae072410VgnVCM10000076192ca2RCRD&amp;vgnextchannel=ba11e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&amp;vgnextfmt=defaultl">http://www.imshealth.com/portal/site/imshealth/menuitem.c76283e8bf81e98f53c753c71ad8c22a/?vgnextoid=96bdd595ae072410VgnVCM10000076192ca2RCRD&amp;vgnextchannel=ba11e590cb4dc310VgnVCM100000a48d2ca2RCRD&amp;vgnextfmt=defaultl</a><a href="#fnref:12" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:13">
<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2014_in_film">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2014_in_film</a><a href="#fnref:13" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:14">
<p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2015-01-13/espn-scores-highest-tv-rating-ever-with-football-finale.html">http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2015-01-13/espn-scores-highest-tv-rating-ever-with-football-finale.html</a><a href="#fnref:14" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Cappio Picks Winning Stocks]]></title>
    <link href="http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/01/05/how-to-pick-winning-stocks/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-05T12:33:49-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cappio.github.io/blog/2015/01/05/how-to-pick-winning-stocks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<!-- Our best advice for anyone who asks that question is to stop and educate themselves before they throw away their money. These days, there are a ton of investment vehicles that are well suited for retail investors, such as ETFs, Index/Mutual Funds, and the more modern roboadvisors, like Wealthfront and Betterment. However, you want to retain control and understand where you money is going, stocks will always be a sensible choice. While  "stock picking" is inherently risky, there are many methods to reduce this risk and maximize your chances of growing your portfolio. -->


<p>One of the most frequent questions we get emailed is &ldquo;how does Cappio work?&rdquo; What powers Cappio is not some Wall Street wizardry, it&rsquo;s tried and true methodology using fundamental analysis. As a quick refresher, fundamental analysis is the process of researching a company based on what they do, how they make money, and it&rsquo;s financial data.</p>

<p>Usually this is a process that can take a couple hours, if not days for a novice. Luckily, an accounting professor by the name of Joseph Piotroski at the University of Chicago formalized many fundamental metrics that should be used when evaluating a company. We’ve added a few comparative metrics to the Cappio algorithm to make it more comphrensive and computational. Below is a video summarizing the methodology we will go over in this post:</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/bDedohLsEwo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>




<!--more-->


<h1>Breaking it Down</h1>

<p>Determining if a company is financially stable can seem subjective and daunting. Cappio breaks down the financial data into four domains to help analysze the company from the top down:</p>

<h3>Industry</h3>

<p>A healthy company should be growing faster and capturing the market it is in. To get a general idea, we can take a look at some common ratios and compare the company to industry averages.</p>

<p><img src="http://note.io/1yummND"></p>

<p>If you need a refresher on any of these terms, Cappio has easy to understand tooltips for every one of these metrics. You can read them by hovering over the terms you are confused about in the app.</p>

<h3>Valuation</h3>

<p>Similar to the Industry section, Valuation helps compare a company to it&rsquo;s top three competitors. Also like in the Industry section you can find explanations of the terms by highlighting them in the app. Generally, the first seven metrics should be higher than competitors and the last three should be lower.</p>

<p><img src="http://note.io/14fzjO7"></p>

<h3>Fundamentals</h3>

<p>The fundamentals of a company involve diving into three major financial statements, the balance sheet, income statement, and cash flow statement. These three are used in tandem to find out if the company is making and retaining money.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/uimblUe.png"></p>

<p>Some specific metrics to look out for:</p>

<ul>
<li>Is the revenue growing?</li>
<li>Is the net income growing?</li>
<li>Is the current ratio (a measure of how able they are to pay off short term debt) not too far over 1.0?</li>
<li>Is the free cash flow (money in the bank) increasing?</li>
</ul>


<h3>Management Effectiveness and Profitability</h3>

<p>As a rule of thumb, you can gauge a company&rsquo;s management effectiveness by taking a look at the Return on Assets (RoA) and Return on Equity (RoE.) It&rsquo;s always a good sign to see them both increasing compared to the previous year and in well-ranked among its competitors.</p>

<p>To get an idea of the company&rsquo;s profitability, take a look at the Operating and Profit Margins to make sure they are positive and increasing.</p>

<p><img src="http://i.imgur.com/j7hk2kE.png"></p>

<h3>Bringing It All Together</h3>

<p>As an overview, this methodology helps you get a good idea of how a potential investment stands against it&rsquo;s industry, competitors, and past performance. It may not be the most fun thing to do but you can cover a lot of bases and reduce your risk if you following simple checklists like these. I&rsquo;d also like to note that always helps to look at an investment holistically. Evaluating growth is subjective and the answer can&rsquo;t be found in just numbers. This is where where keeping up with current events and formulating your own opinions comes into play.</p>

<p>Keep in mind there&rsquo;s no company that is going to fulfill every criteria. However, a company that meets most of them is a solid investment. The reason is simple - a fundamentally strong company is making money and growing. As a company grows, so does the value of the company and therefore, the stock price increases over time.</p>

<p>Love to hear your thoughts on how you invest or any questions you have in the comments below!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Beginner Investor's Guide to the Oil Price Drop]]></title>
    <link href="http://cappio.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/a-beginner-investors-guide-to-the-oil-price-drop/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-17T00:18:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://cappio.github.io/blog/2014/12/17/a-beginner-investors-guide-to-the-oil-price-drop</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You don’t need an economist to tell you oil prices are tanking. Anyone who’s visited the pump recently already has all the evidence they need. However, why oil prices are falling is a much more puzzling. Like any macroeconomic trend, the causes are a combination of political and legal factors. The Economist boils it down to four major factors:</p>

<ul>
<li>Demand is low because of weak economic activity, increased efficiency, and movement towards oil alternatives.</li>
<li>Turmoil in Iraq and Libya, two big oil producers, has not affected their exporting.</li>
<li>America has become the world’s largest oil producer. Though it does not export crude oil, it now imports much less, creating a lot of spare supply.</li>
<li>The Saudis and their Gulf allies have decided not to sacrifice their own market share to restore the price. They can afford to do so since their margins are much higher than countries they detest such as Iran and Russia.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Do these current prices uncover investment opportunities?</h2>

<p>Let’s take a look at four fundamentally sound companies that relate to the current oil prices.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="#glp">Global Partners LP</a></li>
<li><a href="#slb">Schlumberger Limited</a></li>
<li><a href="#xom">Exxon Mobil</a></li>
<li><a href="#dal">Delta Air Lines</a></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h3><a name="glp"></a>Global Partners LP (NYSE: GLP)</h3>

<p>Global Partners LP is one of the largest wholesale distributors of gasoline, home heating oil, and residual oil to wholesalers, retailers and commercial customers in New England and New York. They also have a network of approximately 1,000 independent owners, suppliers and operators of gasoline stations in the Northeast.</p>

<p>They are currently nearing their 52 week low of $32.77 but have been putting up completely solid numbers. Seems like they are oversold and would be a great company to look more into. <a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=GLP">Check out the Cappio report here</a> for more details on it’s fundamentals.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=GLP"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/Rk1m4RC.png" title="GLP Report" ></a></p>

<p>Read more about GLP from <a href="http://www.thestreet.com/story/12976330/1/one-reason-global-partners-glp-stock-is-down-today.html">The Street - One Reason Global Partners is Down</a></p>

<h3><a name="slb"></a>Schlumberger Limited (NYSE: SLB)</h3>

<p>Schlumberger Limited is an oilfield services company that supplies technology, integrated project management, and information solutions to oil and gas exploration and production. With the prices at they are right now, oil producers need Schlumberger technology to increase production and margins. Schlumberger&rsquo;s financials show amazing stability. You can see the solid numbers from <a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=SLB">their Cappio report</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=SLB"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/czrHolJ.png" title="SLB Report" ></a></p>

<p>More indepth analysis on Schlumberger can be found on <a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/2720905-schlumberger-is-the-last-haven-in-a-collapsing-oil-market">Seeking Alpha - Schlumberger is the Last haven in a Collapsing Oil Market</a></p>

<h3><a name="xom"></a>Exxon Mobil (NYSE:XOM)</h3>

<p>Exxon Mobil Corporation explores and produces for crude oil and natural gas. It is considered a safe play way to directly invest in a potential oil rebound because they produce oil and natural gas at a 50/50 ratio. Exxon has historically been accused of it’s large exposure to natural gas, which has greatly lagged the price of crude oil in the last six years. With the recent dip in price this split is now positive. It also explains why the stock of Exxon has lost only 10% of its value in the last five months, while Chevron has lost 17% and BP has lost 19%. <a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=xom">Check the Cappio report here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=xom"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/d3aJLQm.png" title="XOM Report" ></a></p>

<p>Read a more indepth analysis from <a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/2749565-exxonmobil-the-safest-way-to-play-the-oil-rebound">Seeking Alpha - Exxon Mobile is the Safest Way to play the Oil Rebound</a></p>

<h3><a name="dal"></a>Delta Air Lines, Inc. (NYSE: DAL)</h3>

<p>Fuel makes up a third of airlines’ operating costs. According to the Air Transportation Association (ATA), fuel is an airline&rsquo;s second largest expense. With these prices falling their margins are increased substantially. <a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=dal">Here are some of solid fundamentals they are showing on their Cappio report</a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.capp.io/queries/new?query=dal"><img src="http://i.imgur.com/AYb42Qd.png" title="DAL Report" ></a></p>

<p>Read more from: <a href="http://seekingalpha.com/article/2661305-delta-air-lines-to-profit-from-low-oil-price">Seeking Alpha - Delta to Profit from Low Oil Prices</a> and <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/blogs/talking-numbers/cleared-for-takeoff--why-airline-stocks-should-keep-soaring-204133931.html">Yahoo! Finance - Why Airline Stocks Should Keep Soaring</a></p>

<h2>Where are prices headed?</h2>

<p>The general consensus is that the current oil oversupply is economically unsustainable for producers who are not in the Gulf. These producers rely on shale, tar sands, and deep sea oil, which are much more expensive to produce. Eventually, they will need government intervention or will be squeezed out of their market share.</p>

<p>However, it’s impossible to time the market so accurately predicting where oil prices is impractical. OPEC, which produces about 40 percent of the world&rsquo;s crude oil, has been very passive about cutting supply to raise prices. There are claims that they won’t budge on supply if the price drops down to $40.</p>

<p>Luckily the world is no longer solely dependant on OPEC for oil. Russia, America and others are also huge players in the market that have influence on prices. For further information on how the geopolicitcal landscape could quickly cause a rebound in prices, <a href="http://www.marketwatch.com/story/three-scenarios-that-result-in-a-rebound-for-oil-2014-12-15">reference MarketWatch&rsquo;s article</a></p>

<p>Hope you found this article helpful! Be sure to follow us on Twitter and StockTwits for updates on our blog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
